<GameData>
  <Language_zh_Hant_HK>
    <Row>
      <Tag>TXT_KEY_FUNCTIONALITY_INTERNATIONALTRADEROUTESCHANGE_TECH_ENGINEERING</Tag>
      <Text>TradeRoute1</Text>
    </Row>
    <Row>
      <Tag>TXT_KEY_FUNCTIONALITY_BRIDGEBUILDING_TECH_ENGINEERING</Tag>
      <Text>BridgesOnRivers</Text>
    </Row>
    <Row>
      <Tag>TXT_KEY_FUNCTIONALITY_INTERNATIONALTRADEROUTESCHANGE_TECH_BIOLOGY</Tag>
      <Text>TradeRoute1</Text>
    </Row>
    <Row>
      <Tag>TXT_KEY_FUNCTIONALITY_EMBARKEDMOVECHANGE_TECH_STEAM_POWER</Tag>
      <Text>EmbarkSpeed1</Text>
    </Row>
    <Row>
      <Tag>TXT_KEY_FUNCTIONALITY_INTERNATIONALTRADEROUTESCHANGE_TECH_RAILROAD</Tag>
      <Text>TradeRoute1</Text>
    </Row>
    <Row>
      <Tag>TXT_KEY_FUNCTIONALITY_RESEARCHAGREEMENTTRADINGALLOWED_TECH_EDUCATION</Tag>
      <Text>ResearchAgreements</Text>
    </Row>
    <Row>
      <Tag>TXT_KEY_FUNCTIONALITY_DEFENSIVEPACTTRADINGALLOWED_TECH_CHIVALRY</Tag>
      <Text>DefPact</Text>
    </Row>
    <Row>
      <Tag>TXT_KEY_FUNCTIONALITY_INTERNATIONALTRADEROUTESCHANGE_TECH_COMPASS</Tag>
      <Text>TradeRoute1</Text>
    </Row>
    <Row>
      <Tag>TXT_KEY_FUNCTIONALITY_OPENBORDERSTRADINGALLOWED_TECH_CIVIL_SERVICE</Tag>
      <Text>OpenBorders</Text>
    </Row>
    <Row>
      <Tag>TXT_KEY_FUNCTIONALITY_EMBARKEDMOVECHANGE_TECH_ASTRONOMY</Tag>
      <Text>EmbarkSpeed1</Text>
    </Row>
    <Row>
      <Tag>TXT_KEY_FUNCTIONALITY_EMBARKEDALLWATERPASSAGE_TECH_ASTRONOMY</Tag>
      <Text>OceanCross</Text>
    </Row>
    <Row>
      <Tag>TXT_KEY_FUNCTIONALITY_ALLOWSWORLDCONGRESS_TECH_PRINTING_PRESS</Tag>
      <Text>WorldCongress</Text>
    </Row>
    <Row>
      <Tag>TXT_KEY_FUNCTIONALITY_INTERNATIONALTRADEROUTESCHANGE_TECH_BANKING</Tag>
      <Text>TradeRoute1</Text>
    </Row>
    <Row>
      <Tag>TXT_KEY_FUNCTIONALITY_INTERNATIONALTRADEROUTESCHANGE_TECH_PENICILIN</Tag>
      <Text>TradeRoute1</Text>
    </Row>
    <Row>
      <Tag>TXT_KEY_FUNCTIONALITY_ALLOWSEMBARKING_TECH_OPTICS</Tag>
      <Text>Embark</Text>
    </Row>
    <Row>
      <Tag>TXT_KEY_FUNCTIONALITY_ALLOWEMBASSYTRADINGALLOWED_TECH_WRITING</Tag>
      <Text>Embassy</Text>
    </Row>
    <Row>
      <Tag>TXT_KEY_FUNCTIONALITY_INTERNATIONALTRADEROUTESCHANGE_TECH_ANIMAL_HUSBANDRY</Tag>
      <Text>TradeRoute1</Text>
    </Row>
    <Row>
      <Tag>TXT_KEY_FUNCTIONALITY_INTERNATIONALTRADEROUTESCHANGE_TECH_SAILING</Tag>
      <Text>TradeRoute1</Text>
    </Row>
    <Row>
      <Tag>TXT_KEY_FUNCTIONALITY_MAPVISIBLE_TECH_SATELLITES</Tag>
      <Text>RevealMap</Text>
    </Row>
    <Row>
      <Tag>TXT_KEY_FUNCTIONALITY_EXTRAVOTESPERDIPLOMAT_TECH_GLOBALIZATION</Tag>
      <Text>ExtraVotesPerDiplomat1</Text>
    </Row>
    <Row>
      <Tag>TXT_KEY_FUNCTIONALITY_INFLUENCESPREADMODIFIER_TECH_INTERNET</Tag>
      <Text>TourismBy100</Text>
    </Row>
    <Row>
      <Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_MYTHOLOGY_DESC</Tag>
      <Text>神話</Text>
    </Row>
    <Row>
      <Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_MYTHOLOGY_CIV</Tag>
      <Text>
		  Mythology is the attempt to explain natural phenomena by imagination and stories originated from different civilizations. These stories concern the origin and the nature of the world, as well as the lives and activities of deities, heroes and mythological creatures and the origins and significance of the cult and ritual practices. In an era which the writing system was not mature, mythologies were particularly told by oral practices, propagated in an oral-poetic tradition.
		  [NEWLINE][NEWLINE]The word ‘Mythology’ originates from the word ‘myth’, which comes from the Greek ‘mythos’. Ancient Greek mythology refers to stories originated from Greece describing a period around the 18th century B.C. The heroes in the mythology usually had superpower. The myths of the heroes of the Trojan war had become part of the tradition of Homer’s epic poems, including the Iliad and the Odyssey, which tell about the battles and events during the weeks of a quarrel between king Agamenon and the warrior Achilles.
		  [NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Aside from the narrative deposit in ancient Greek Literature, pictorial representations of gods, deities, heroes and mythic episodes featured in ancient vase paintings and the decoration of many other artifacts. Greek mythology has had an extensive influence on the culture, arts, and literature of Western civilization and remains part of Western heritage and language.
	  </Text>
    </Row>
    <Row>
      <Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_MYTHOLOGY_HELP</Tag>
	  <Text>Allows you to build the [COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT]Shrine[ENDCOLOR], the first [ICON_PEACE] Faith producing building in the game.</Text>
	</Row>
    <Row>
      <Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_MYTHOLOGY_QUOTE</Tag>
      <Text>
		  “Men are so quick to blame the gods: they say that we devise their misery. But they themselves- in their depravity- design grief greater than the griefs that fate assigns.”
		  [NEWLINE]- Homer, The Odyssey
	  </Text>
    </Row>
	<Row>
      <Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_SAILING_CIV</Tag>
      <Text>Sailing is the art of harnessing the power of the wind to move a boat over the water. To be successful, sailing required the mastery of a number of diverse skills. First, the culture must be able to construct a seaworthy craft. Second, they must be able to construct some sort of sturdy sheets (sails) which can catch the wind and transmit its energy to the hull. Third they must be able to build the various ropes and cleats and pulleys used to control the ship's sails, and finally they must be able to successfully navigate the vessel from point to point without getting lost or capsizing or suffering some other misfortune.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]The earliest recorded evidence of watercraft can be found in illustrations in Egypt which date from around 4,000 BC. As a riparian (river-based) civilization, the Egyptians were excellent sailors. Many of their vessels contained both oars and sails, the former being used when the winds weren't strong enough or weren't coming from a favorable direction.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]By 3000 BC the Egyptians were venturing out into the Mediterranean Sea in their vessels, steering the lengthy journey across the open water to Crete and later Phoenicia. The Egyptians also sailed down the coast of Africa, looking for knowledge, trade and treasure.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]The earliest warships - biremes and triremes and the like - were powered by oar and sail and possessed rams or beaks on their prows. During battle the helmsman would attempt to ram the enemy vessel at high speed, while avoiding the enemy's earnest attempts to do the same thing. Some vessels were equipped with archers to fire at enemy craft from longer distance, while others had soldiers aboard; these vessels sought to come alongside the enemy craft so that their soldiers could board the other ship and take it by storm.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]The Greeks - especially the Athenians and the island colonies - were masters at naval warfare. One of the reasons that they were able to defeat their much larger and more powerful neighbor, Persia, was that the Athenian navy dominated the Aegean Sea and thus constantly threatened the Persians' increasingly lengthy supply chain.</Text>
    </Row>
    <Row>
      <Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_CIVIL_SERVICE_CIV</Tag>
      <Text>The term "civil service" is generally used to describe the parts of a government in which individuals are employed on the basis of merit rather than because of political patronage or being born into a certain class or because the person is related to the current ruler. In the United States federal government, for instance, the highest posts in the bureaucracy are appointed by the president. They are "political appointments" and will likely change with each new administration. Ranks below the highest points are filled with permanent "civil servants," who generally hold their positions from administration to administration, no matter which party wins.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]One of the earliest examples of a civil service can be found in the Qin Dynasty of China (ca. 210 BC), under which employment in the bureaucracy was merit-based. Over time this system gradually was corrupted and employment in the bureaucracy once again became based upon class rather than merit. Three hundred years later the merit system was reapplied (under the Sui and Tang Dynasties), and it remained in effect for some centuries.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Historically, many civilizations have followed a similar pattern to the Chinese: over time the bureaucracy becomes increasingly corrupt and inefficient until eventually stringent reforms are enacted to improve the government's efficiency. These make things better for a while until standards begin to be relaxed in favor of family or connections, and the cycle begins all over again.</Text>
    </Row>
    <Row>
      <Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_LAW_DESC</Tag>
      <Text>法律</Text>
    </Row>
    <Row>
      <Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_LAW_CIV</Tag>
      <Text>Added using Indie Stone Tech Tree Editor.</Text>
    </Row>
    <Row>
      <Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_LAW_HELP</Tag>
      <Text>Added using Indie Stone Tech Tree Editor.</Text>
    </Row>
    <Row>
      <Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_LAW_QUOTE</Tag>
      <Text>'Some Famous Quote' - Some Famous Person</Text>
    </Row>
    <Row>
      <Tag>TXT_KEY_FUNCTIONALITY_ALLOWEMBASSYTRADINGALLOWED_TECH_LAW</Tag>
      <Text>Embassy</Text>
    </Row>
    <Row>
      <Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_COMPLEX_CONSTRUCTION_DESC</Tag>
      <Text>建築構造學</Text>
    </Row>
    <Row>
      <Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_COMPLEX_CONSTRUCTION_CIV</Tag>
      <Text>建築構造學其實就是更精良的砌造術，主要是將鐵和其他金屬加入建築材料的行列。石頭和磚塊經久耐用，但也沉重且限制重重。僅憑磚石無法建造非常高大的建築結構的，建築只能是實心而且要建成金字塔形，否則就會因為無法承受自身重量或是強風而倒塌。[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]相較之下，金屬結構或者與金屬共構的磚石結構，就可以造出高大美觀、結構穩固的建築。採用金屬材料之後，人們就可以建造大跨度橋樑、地下隧道、摩天大樓以及高架道路。沒有建築構造學，世界上那些偉大的城市和美麗的建築都不會存在。</Text>
    </Row>
    <Row>
      <Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_COMPLEX_CONSTRUCTION_HELP</Tag>
      <Text>允許工人在森林單元格建造[COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT]鋸木廠[ENDCOLOR]，提高該單元格的[ICON_PRODUCTION]生產力。還能讓您建造[COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT]競技場[ENDCOLOR]，可提昇帝國[ICON_HAPPINESS_1]的幸福度、幫助城市發展和加快[ICON_GOLDEN_AGE]黃金時代的到來。</Text>
    </Row>
    <Row>
      <Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_COMPLEX_CONSTRUCTION_QUOTE</Tag>
      <Text>[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB]「看一幢建築要看三樣東西--建造地點是否正確；地基是否牢固；建造是否成功。」[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB--約翰·沃爾夫岡·馮·歌德[NEWLINE][TAB]</Text>
    </Row>
    <Row>
      <Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_CURRENCY_CIV</Tag>
      <Text>Currency is a remarkable innovation by which pieces of paper or small discs represent a certain amount of wealth and can be traded to others in return for goods and services. The earliest currencies were metal coins; these were worth whatever was the current value of the metal out of which they were carved. Later on, the currency itself might have little or no intrinsic value - on a desert island, a dollar bill is nothing more than a small rectangular piece of paper - but the currency's issuer (usually a government) assigned it a value, and as long as the issuer remained solvent, the currency was as good as gold, so to speak.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]In the 4th millennium BC, Ancient Egypt used gold bars of a set weight as currency; elsewhere in the Middle East copper ingots were similarly used. In many places in the world metal rings, bracelets and bangles (of gold, silver and jewels) served as both ornamentation and currency.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Throughout history, forgers have always sought to create bogus replicas of the currency at hand. Forgers might create duplicate coins of inferior and cheaper metal than the legal tender, or they might "shave" a bit of metal off of a coin made of precious material. When paper money became the norm for currency the forgers quickly learned how to duplicate the size, color and feel of the paper and copy the pictures and writing on the bills. Forgers are so proficient that most modern currency now comes complete with many advanced security measures, and the time is not far away when each bill will have its own computer chip embedded in the paper.</Text>
    </Row>
    <Row>
      <Tag>TXT_KEY_FUNCTIONALITY_INTERNATIONALTRADEROUTESCHANGE_TECH_CURRENCY</Tag>
      <Text>TradeRoute1</Text>
    </Row>
    <Row>
      <Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_POLITICAL_PHILOSOPHY_DESC</Tag>
      <Text>政治哲學</Text>
    </Row>
    <Row>
      <Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_POLITICAL_PHILOSOPHY_CIV</Tag>
      <Text>Philosophy is the study of reality and man's place in it. The word comes from the Greek/Latin "philosophia," or love of wisdom. It is somewhat separate from religion, which seeks to define and understand some supernatural system - philosophy takes a step back and asks if that supernatural system even exists. Philosophy deals with logic, morality, observation, realism, happiness, life, death, and all of the other big questions.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]The Greeks are generally credited with the invention of philosophy in western civilization. In the 6th century BC Thales of Miletus was the first man known to give a purely natural (non-religious) explanation for the origin of the world. He believed that everything came out of water; this theory was based upon his viewing of fossilized sea animals far inland. This explanation required no creative action by a supernatural being; it was a result of natural properties. Later philosophers would expand upon this most basic theory - except of course for those philosophers who chose to deny that anything exists at all, and those who decided that the world was but a reflection of some other place anyway, and so forth. The problem with examining reality is that the deeper one looks, the more confusing everything gets.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]At its best, philosophy provides tools which one can use to observe and make judgments about the world around them, to think about things that haven't been considered before. Like any other tool it can be used for good or for evil, but philosophy at least seeks to provide the intellectual structure to help one decide which is which.</Text>
    </Row>
    <Row>
      <Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_POLITICAL_PHILOSOPHY_HELP</Tag>
      <Text>Allows you to build the [COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT]Temple[ENDCOLOR], which increases the [ICON_PEACE] Faith output of a city.</Text>
    </Row>
    <Row>
      <Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_POLITICAL_PHILOSOPHY_QUOTE</Tag>
      <Text>[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB]"There is only one good, knowledge, and one evil, ignorance."[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB]  - Socrates[NEWLINE][TAB]</Text>
    </Row>
    <Row>
      <Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_ASSOCIATIVE_THINKING_DESC</Tag>
      <Text>聯想思維</Text>
    </Row>
    <Row>
      <Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_ASSOCIATIVE_THINKING_CIV</Tag>
      <Text>Added using Indie Stone Tech Tree Editor.</Text>
    </Row>
    <Row>
      <Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_ASSOCIATIVE_THINKING_HELP</Tag>
      <Text>Added using Indie Stone Tech Tree Editor.</Text>
    </Row>
    <Row>
      <Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_ASSOCIATIVE_THINKING_QUOTE</Tag>
      <Text>'Some Famous Quote' - Some Famous Person</Text>
    </Row>
    <Row>
      <Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_NATURAL_PHILOSOPHY_DESC</Tag>
      <Text>自然哲學</Text>
    </Row>
    <Row>
      <Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_NATURAL_PHILOSOPHY_CIV</Tag>
      <Text>Added using Indie Stone Tech Tree Editor.</Text>
    </Row>
    <Row>
      <Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_NATURAL_PHILOSOPHY_HELP</Tag>
      <Text>Added using Indie Stone Tech Tree Editor.</Text>
    </Row>
    <Row>
      <Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_NATURAL_PHILOSOPHY_QUOTE</Tag>
      <Text>'Some Famous Quote' - Some Famous Person</Text>
    </Row>
    <Row>
      <Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_THEOLOGY_CIV</Tag>
      <Text>神學是對宗教的研究，神學家研究宗教的傳統和教義。神學最早可以追溯到古典的希臘人，他們擁有著極度豐富的神話傳說和宗教傳統。在西元一、二世紀時，猶太教的宗教學術最為昌盛。在西元200年，耶路撒冷塔木德經開始流傳開來，這是一本記載猶太人口耳相傳的傳統的書，並在接下來的兩個世紀裡不斷被補充修正。[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]神學是很重要的，它在人類歷史上有著舉足輕重的地位。因為宗教衝突而死去的人不計其數，一直到今天仍然未曾間斷。羅馬人因為基督教徒的激進宗教不承認羅馬人的神而屠殺他們，基督教徒又因為宗教衝突屠殺猶太人和穆斯林甚至自己人。神學家和基督教改革家馬丁·路德的《九十五條論綱》中，質疑為籌措資金建造聖彼得大教堂而販賣贖罪券等問題引發了歐洲數百年來殘酷的宗教衝突。如果要解決當今世界激進的穆斯林和西方世界之間的宗教戰爭，神學將是至關重要的一環。</Text>
    </Row>
    <Row>
      <Tag>TXT_KEY_FUNCTIONALITY_RESEARCHAGREEMENTTRADINGALLOWED_TECH_UNIVERSITY_EDUCATION</Tag>
      <Text>ResearchAgreements</Text>
    </Row>
    <Row>
      <Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_UNIVERSITY_EDUCATION_DESC</Tag>
      <Text>大學教育</Text>
    </Row>
    <Row>
      <Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_UNIVERSITY_EDUCATION_CIV</Tag>
      <Text>所謂教育就是人類學習的過程。很顯然的從有人類以來就有教育。早期的教育多半是非正式的，父母將生活知識口頭傳授給孩子們，包括如何處理家務、外出打獵、躲避老虎襲擊等等。當部落擴張繁榮起來之後，村裡的老人和殘疾人主要負責教導孩子們這些知識，而較健康的成年男子則主要負責採集糧食、製造器物或是作戰。最後非常富裕的部落便可能出現專為權貴之子設計的正式課程。而當文明夠成熟了，就會開始體認到全民教育的重要性。[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]古埃及時代，祭司們負責教導貴族子弟。這些孩子在埃及的學校中學習閱讀、寫作、宗教、歷史、科學、醫學、數學以及其他進階課程。埃及的競爭對手美索不達米亞地區，也有十分相似的教育系統。其教育目的主要是培育祭司和書記（可能是抄寫員、圖書館員或講師）。學生們學習的課程也包括閱讀、寫作、宗教、法律、醫學和占星學。在中國，教育最早出現在約3000年前。閱讀、寫作、公民責任、禮儀和音樂是古代中國學生的核心課程。[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]在馬雅文化中，教育同樣掌握在祭司手中。受過良好教育的祭司階層擔任部落酋長和其他市民的重要顧問。為了成為祭司，學生們同樣需要努力學習歷史、寫作、神學、醫學和曆法系統。</Text>
    </Row>
    <Row>
      <Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_UNIVERSITY_EDUCATION_HELP</Tag>
      <Text>Allows you to build the [COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT]University[ENDCOLOR], which boosts [ICON_RESEARCH] Science. Also provides new [ICON_RESEARCH] Science-related abilities, like the [COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT]Research Agreement[ENDCOLOR], which is a special deal that may be made with other players in the game.</Text>
    </Row>
    <Row>
      <Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_UNIVERSITY_EDUCATION_QUOTE</Tag>
      <Text>[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB]"Education is the best provision for old age."[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB]  - Aristotle[NEWLINE][TAB]</Text>
    </Row>
    <Row>
      <Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_HOLISTIC_WORLDIEW_DESC</Tag>
      <Text>整體世界觀</Text>
    </Row>
    <Row>
      <Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_HOLISTIC_WORLDIEW_CIV</Tag>
      <Text>Added using Indie Stone Tech Tree Editor.</Text>
    </Row>
    <Row>
      <Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_HOLISTIC_WORLDIEW_HELP</Tag>
      <Text>Added using Indie Stone Tech Tree Editor.</Text>
    </Row>
    <Row>
      <Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_HOLISTIC_WORLDIEW_QUOTE</Tag>
      <Text>'Some Famous Quote' - Some Famous Person</Text>
    </Row>
    <Row>
      <Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_RATIONALISM_DESC</Tag>
      <Text>理性主義</Text>
    </Row>
    <Row>
      <Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_RATIONALISM_CIV</Tag>
      <Text>Added using Indie Stone Tech Tree Editor.</Text>
    </Row>
    <Row>
      <Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_RATIONALISM_HELP</Tag>
      <Text>Added using Indie Stone Tech Tree Editor.</Text>
    </Row>
    <Row>
      <Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_RATIONALISM_QUOTE</Tag>
      <Text>'Some Famous Quote' - Some Famous Person</Text>
    </Row>
    <Row>
      <Tag>TXT_KEY_FUNCTIONALITY_EMBARKEDMOVECHANGE_TECH_SCIENTIFIC_METHOD</Tag>
      <Text>EmbarkSpeed1</Text>
    </Row>
    <Row>
      <Tag>TXT_KEY_FUNCTIONALITY_EMBARKEDALLWATERPASSAGE_TECH_SCIENTIFIC_METHOD</Tag>
      <Text>OceanCross</Text>
    </Row>
    <Row>
      <Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_SCIENTIFIC_METHOD_DESC</Tag>
      <Text>科學方法</Text>
    </Row>
    <Row>
      <Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_SCIENTIFIC_METHOD_CIV</Tag>
      <Text>科學方法是一種理解世界乃至整個宇宙的方法。透過細心的觀察和試驗，科學家創造理論來解釋某種現象。如果其他的科學家能夠通過試驗來確認此理論，則此理論被接受為「經驗」（試驗的）定律（至少在有新的觀測或者試驗事實能反對這一切之前是的）。如果某個科學家的試驗是無法被別人複製的，那麼他的理論是該被質疑的。[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]儘管在當今世界的發達國家中，科學理論是主流，但是科學理論並不是唯一的方法。一些人還是相信神的天啟—比如說某種聖書—能夠解釋宇宙的一切的。如果觀測或試驗事實有違天啟，那麼他們認為在觀測或試驗中肯定存在缺陷甚至造假的地方。這兩種觀察世界的方法已經互相爭鬥了無數個世紀，而且也將繼續爭鬥下去。</Text>
    </Row>
    <Row>
      <Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_SCIENTIFIC_METHOD_HELP</Tag>
      <Text>Allows you to build the [COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT]Caravel[ENDCOLOR], the first Naval Unit capable of exploring the world's oceans, and the [COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT]Observatory[ENDCOLOR], which provides a significant [ICON_RESEARCH] Science boost. Also allows embarked land units to cross ocean tiles.</Text>
    </Row>
    <Row>
      <Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_SCIENTIFIC_METHOD_QUOTE</Tag>
      <Text>[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB]"Joyfully to the breeze royal Odysseus spread his sail, and with his rudder skillfully he steered."[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB]  - Homer[NEWLINE][TAB]</Text>
    </Row>
    <Row>
      <Tag>TXT_KEY_FUNCTIONALITY_EMBARKEDALLWATERPASSAGE_TECH_NAVIGATION</Tag>
      <Text>OceanCross</Text>
    </Row>
    <Row>
      <Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_PRINTING_PRESS_CIV</Tag>
      <Text>雖然活字印刷術是中國發明的；就所知，第一座機械化印刷機則是十五世紀中葉由德國的約翰尼斯·古騰堡所發明。最早期的印刷機是木製的，在設計上和地中海地區幾個世紀以來用以壓搾葡萄酒和橄欖油的機器非常相似。[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]最早的印刷機將活字反向排列且緊密地固定在一個木製的「壓盤」上。先在活字上塗一層油墨，然後再放上紙張。技工給壓盤上緊螺絲加壓，使紙張接觸帶有油墨的活字。然後技工取下紙張並給活字重新上墨，如此反覆操作。古騰堡的印刷機每小時可以印250頁（單面印刷）。這樣的設計持地續使用了三百多年，直到金屬印刷機的出現。十九世紀時，印刷機開始使用蒸汽作為動力，印刷速度可以達到每小時7500張。[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]印刷對人類知識的傳承不容忽視，在印刷機出現以前，印製的書數量極為稀少，每一本書的價格超過一個普通工人一年的工資。印刷機發明時，劍橋大學圖書館只藏有100多本書；但在極短的一段時間後，人們就普遍能夠購買聖經及其他書籍了。不到60年，第一本印刷的「新聞書」（報紙的前身）便在英格蘭問世。</Text>
    </Row>
    <Row>
      <Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_GUNPOWDER_CIV</Tag>
      <Text>火藥又有「黑火藥」之名，起源於中國。其歷史可以上溯到西元9世紀，是中國方士們在煉製長生不老藥（雖然事實上正好相反）的過程中偶然發現的產物。火藥是硫磺、木炭和硝酸鉀的混合物，遇火即能迅速猛烈的燃燒，並且產生大量的煙塵，因此可用來作為火器的推進燃料，並且製作煙火。中國人用火藥製作了簡單的炸彈和火箭以抵禦蒙古侵略者。蒙古人征服了中國以後，這些火器便被蒙古人用來對付其他人。[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]到了12世紀上半葉，阿拉伯世界已經學會了火藥的相關知識。部分歷史文獻指稱馬木留克於西元1260年的阿音札魯特戰役中首次使用加農炮對抗蒙古人，但此說法仍有爭議。第一個關於「手銃」的記載出現在14世紀的阿拉伯文手稿中。[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]歐洲則在12世紀中葉左右獲得了關於火藥的知識。他們利用「濕製法」提高了火藥的品質，在火藥粉末中加入液體讓火藥結成更大的顆粒（像玉米粒），提高火藥的穩定性。[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]此後一直到19世紀「無煙」火藥發明前，火藥一直用於槍炮等火器。這種新產品燃燒較完全，產生的煙塵更少，進而取代了舊式的黑火藥。</Text>
    </Row>
    <Row>
      <Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_LIBERALISM_DESC</Tag>
      <Text>自由主義</Text>
    </Row>
    <Row>
      <Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_LIBERALISM_CIV</Tag>
      <Text>Added using Indie Stone Tech Tree Editor.</Text>
    </Row>
    <Row>
      <Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_LIBERALISM_HELP</Tag>
      <Text>Added using Indie Stone Tech Tree Editor.</Text>
    </Row>
    <Row>
      <Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_LIBERALISM_QUOTE</Tag>
      <Text>'Some Famous Quote' - Some Famous Person</Text>
    </Row>
    <Row>
      <Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_NAVAL_ARCHITECTURE_DESC</Tag>
      <Text>船舶工程學</Text>
    </Row>
    <Row>
      <Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_NAVAL_ARCHITECTURE_CIV</Tag>
      <Text>Architecture can be considered both an art and a science. Encompassing everything from the initial planning and design of a structure, to the actual construction process, architecture has been a crucial element of the building process since ancient times. One of the earliest known discussions of architecture and its principles, "De Architectura," was written by the Roman architect Vitruvius in the first century BC. A ten volume set comprising all of the most intricate details of Roman construction methods, Vitruvius's work is widely recognized today as a crucial development in the evolution of the architectural design process.</Text>
    </Row>
    <Row>
      <Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_NAVAL_ARCHITECTURE_HELP</Tag>
      <Text>Allows you to construct multiple Wonders that can boost [ICON_CULTURE] Culture, [ICON_RESEARCH] Science and [ICON_HAPPINESS_1] Happiness.</Text>
    </Row>
    <Row>
      <Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_NAVAL_ARCHITECTURE_QUOTE</Tag>
      <Text>[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB]"Architecture begins where engineering ends."[NEWLINE] - Walter Gropius[NEWLINE][TAB]</Text>
    </Row>
    <Row>
      <Tag>TXT_KEY_FUNCTIONALITY_EMBARKEDMOVECHANGE_TECH_NAVAL_ARCHITECTURE</Tag>
      <Text>EmbarkSpeed10</Text>
    </Row>
    <Row>
      <Tag>TXT_KEY_FUNCTIONALITY_DEFENSIVEPACTTRADINGALLOWED_TECH_CIVIL_SERVICE</Tag>
      <Text>DefPact</Text>
    </Row>
    <Row>
      <Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_UNNAMED_TECH_1_DESC</Tag>
      <Text>Unnamed Tech 1</Text>
    </Row>
    <Row>
      <Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_UNNAMED_TECH_1_QUOTE</Tag>
      <Text>'Some Famous Quote' - Some Famous Person</Text>
    </Row>
    <Row>
      <Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_UNNAMED_TECH_1_HELP</Tag>
      <Text>Added using Indie Stone Tech Tree Editor.</Text>
    </Row>
    <Row>
      <Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_UNNAMED_TECH_1_CIV</Tag>
      <Text>Added using Indie Stone Tech Tree Editor.</Text>
    </Row>
    <Row>
      <Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_NATIONALISM_DESC</Tag>
      <Text>民族主義</Text>
    </Row>
    <Row>
      <Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_NATIONALISM_CIV</Tag>
      <Text>Added using Indie Stone Tech Tree Editor.</Text>
    </Row>
    <Row>
      <Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_NATIONALISM_HELP</Tag>
      <Text>Added using Indie Stone Tech Tree Editor.</Text>
    </Row>
    <Row>
      <Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_NATIONALISM_QUOTE</Tag>
      <Text>'Some Famous Quote' - Some Famous Person</Text>
    </Row>
    <Row>
      <Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_GEOLOGY_DESC</Tag>
      <Text>地質學</Text>
    </Row>
    <Row>
      <Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_GEOLOGY_CIV</Tag>
      <Text>
Archaeology is the study of the remnants of ancient people to learn about their culture, art, architecture, and history. Archaeologists study building ruins, burial mounds, trash heaps, ancient carvings hidden in caves, and long drowned ships on the bottom of the ocean.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Although people have no doubt been interested in the lives of those who came before them for as long as there have been people, archaeology as a science began in 15th century Renaissance Europe, when people began to study and emulate the art and architecture of Ancient Greece and Rome and the wealthy nobility of Italy - popes, merchants and heads of state - began to collect antiquities. As these became more scarce, they sponsored excavations to find more loot.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Archaeology was put on a more scientific basis in the 19th century through the efforts of German scholars like Heinrich Schliemann, who examined early Greek civilization in Troy and Mycenae.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Today archaeologists are studying every aspect of ancient humanity, from our earliest ancestor almost up to our great-great grandparents. Their tools are incredibly sophisticated, allowing ever more insight into the lives of our forebears.</Text>
    </Row>
    <Row>
      <Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_GEOLOGY_HELP</Tag>
      <Text>Allows you to build the [COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT]Museum[ENDCOLOR], which provides a large boost to [ICON_CULTURE] Culture when built in a city. Also provides other bonuses relating to [ICON_CULTURE] Culture.</Text>
    </Row>
    <Row>
      <Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_GEOLOGY_QUOTE</Tag>
      <Text>[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB]"Those who cannot remember the past are condemned to repeat it."[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB]  - George Santayana[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB][TAB]</Text>
    </Row>
    <Row>
      <Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_GENETICS_DESC</Tag>
      <Text>遺傳學</Text>
    </Row>
    <Row>
      <Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_GENETICS_CIV</Tag>
      <Text>Added using Indie Stone Tech Tree Editor.</Text>
    </Row>
    <Row>
      <Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_GENETICS_HELP</Tag>
      <Text>Added using Indie Stone Tech Tree Editor.</Text>
    </Row>
    <Row>
      <Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_GENETICS_QUOTE</Tag>
      <Text>'Some Famous Quote' - Some Famous Person</Text>
    </Row>
    <Row>
      <Tag>TXT_KEY_FUNCTIONALITY_INTERNATIONALTRADEROUTESCHANGE_TECH_STEAM_POWER</Tag>
      <Text>TradeRoute1</Text>
    </Row>
    <Row>
      <Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_MARXISM_DESC</Tag>
      <Text>馬克思主義</Text>
    </Row>
    <Row>
      <Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_MARXISM_CIV</Tag>
      <Text>Added using Indie Stone Tech Tree Editor.</Text>
    </Row>
    <Row>
      <Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_MARXISM_HELP</Tag>
      <Text>Added using Indie Stone Tech Tree Editor.</Text>
    </Row>
    <Row>
      <Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_MARXISM_QUOTE</Tag>
      <Text>'Some Famous Quote' - Some Famous Person</Text>
    </Row>
    <Row>
      <Tag>TXT_KEY_FUNCTIONALITY_EMBARKEDMOVECHANGE_TECH_STEAM_BOAT</Tag>
      <Text>EmbarkSpeed1</Text>
    </Row>
    <Row>
      <Tag>TXT_KEY_FUNCTIONALITY_INTERNATIONALTRADEROUTESCHANGE_TECH_STEAM_BOAT</Tag>
      <Text>TradeRoute1</Text>
    </Row>
    <Row>
      <Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_STEAM_BOAT_DESC</Tag>
      <Text>蒸汽船</Text>
    </Row>
    <Row>
      <Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_STEAM_BOAT_CIV</Tag>
      <Text>水加熱會產生蒸汽。蒸氣膨脹產生壓力，蒸汽機可以使用部分的能量來推動活塞或轉子。蒸汽力量的原理早在古代希臘就被人所知曉，但當時的人類還不知道如何有效地運用；直到17世紀末時英國人湯瑪斯·塞維利製造了一臺蒸汽驅動的泵，可以將水從礦坑裡打上來。而在1765年詹姆斯·瓦特大幅地增強了蒸汽機的效能，使其可以運用在更多的地方。1802年蒸汽機開始被安裝在船隻上，而1825年蒸汽鐵路開始正式運行。[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]蒸汽機對世界的工業和交通發展是一次徹底的革命。在一個世紀之內，地球上就被縱橫交錯的鐵軌與蒸汽船航線網所覆蓋。大型蒸汽動力的工廠開始數以百萬計的製造各式商品，當然也包括軍用品。工業化國家享受到了蒸汽機帶來的龐大生產力與財富及污染。蒸汽機的主要燃料，煤礦，在各地被瘋狂地開採。英國的全球戰略部署就主要是保護全球海洋戰略位置上的煤礦補給站的安全。[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]蒸汽機終究被更有效率更少污染的內燃機所取代。但是在石油之前，蒸汽是王者，沒有蒸汽動力就沒有現代的世界。</Text>
    </Row>
    <Row>
      <Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_STEAM_BOAT_HELP</Tag>
      <Text>Allows you to build the [COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT]Ironclad[ENDCOLOR], a powerful warship especially suited to combat in coastal waters.</Text>
    </Row>
    <Row>
      <Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_STEAM_BOAT_QUOTE</Tag>
      <Text>[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB]"The nations of the West hope that by means of steam communication all the world will become as one family."[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB]  - Townsend Harris[NEWLINE][TAB]</Text>
    </Row>
    <Row>
      <Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_REPLACEABLE_PARTS_CIV</Tag>
      <Text>可互換部件是在生產過程中製造大量相同的物件，最終成為可交互替換的部件。這種製程有利於提高生產速度和獲利空間，而且還推進了19世紀的工業革命。[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]推動可互換部件發展的一個主要原因是將槍枝大量分配給士兵的想法。最初，火槍是由工匠製造的，每一把火槍彼此間都會有略微的不同，就好像有的工匠喜歡製作長一點的槍枝，而有的則喜歡稍微大一點或者小一點的扳機。對個人來說，這不算是個問題，因為如果他的火槍壞了，他可以將槍交還給製造這把槍的工匠來修理。但是對於一把有上千枝火槍的軍隊來說，這種方法就行不通了。[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]然而，如果所有的火槍都有統一規格，一把故障火槍上的部件就可以用於修理其他的火槍。再說，一位士兵只要學會使用其中一把槍就可以使用其他相同的槍，而不需要再重新訓練了。[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]如今，幾乎世界上所有的工業產品都是用可互換部件製造的。過去的工匠業則成了藝術家，他們製造的物品對於大眾消費者來說是過於昂貴了。</Text>
    </Row>
    <Row>
      <Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_FASCISM_DESC</Tag>
      <Text>法西斯主義</Text>
    </Row>
    <Row>
      <Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_FASCISM_CIV</Tag>
      <Text>Added using Indie Stone Tech Tree Editor.</Text>
    </Row>
    <Row>
      <Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_FASCISM_HELP</Tag>
      <Text>Added using Indie Stone Tech Tree Editor.</Text>
    </Row>
    <Row>
      <Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_FASCISM_QUOTE</Tag>
      <Text>'Some Famous Quote' - Some Famous Person</Text>
    </Row>
    <Row>
      <Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_ELECTRONICS_CIV</Tag>
      <Text>電子學的研究範疇便是電子在受控狀態下，在各種包括真空等各種介質中的行為模式。這門科學與電學科技並不相同，電學主要和電流的產生和輸送有關。電子學直到1950年代才從無線電學中獨立出來，成為一門學科。[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]電子電路主要被分為兩大類：類比電路和數位電路。類比電路通常由基礎電路排列組合而成，使用連續電壓，不過現今已經少用全為類比的電路了。數位電路為現代電腦和可程式邏輯控制器打下基礎，也是「邏輯代數」（即0與1）最常見的實質體現。[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]電子學的研究和發展和數學的發展緊密相關，擅長後者是學習前者的先決條件。無論是創造還是分析複雜的電路，都需要能夠解出帶有多項未知變數（比如某個特定位點的電壓和電流）的線性系統。因此，設計自動軟體套件可以大幅提升電路設計效率，這可是一件做起來相當微妙的工作。</Text>
    </Row>
    <Row>
      <Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_PESTICIDES_DESC</Tag>
      <Text>農藥</Text>
    </Row>
    <Row>
      <Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_PESTICIDES_CIV</Tag>
      <Text>Added using Indie Stone Tech Tree Editor.</Text>
    </Row>
    <Row>
      <Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_PESTICIDES_HELP</Tag>
      <Text>Added using Indie Stone Tech Tree Editor.</Text>
    </Row>
    <Row>
      <Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_PESTICIDES_QUOTE</Tag>
      <Text>'Some Famous Quote' - Some Famous Person</Text>
    </Row>
    <Row>
      <Tag>TXT_KEY_FUNCTIONALITY_INTERNATIONALTRADEROUTESCHANGE_TECH_ELECTRONICS</Tag>
      <Text>TradeRoute1</Text>
    </Row>
    <Row>
      <Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_BIOTECHNOLOGY_DESC</Tag>
      <Text>生物技術</Text>
    </Row>
    <Row>
      <Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_BIOTECHNOLOGY_CIV</Tag>
      <Text>Added using Indie Stone Tech Tree Editor.</Text>
    </Row>
    <Row>
      <Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_BIOTECHNOLOGY_HELP</Tag>
      <Text>Added using Indie Stone Tech Tree Editor.</Text>
    </Row>
    <Row>
      <Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_BIOTECHNOLOGY_QUOTE</Tag>
      <Text>'Some Famous Quote' - Some Famous Person</Text>
    </Row>
    <Row>
      <Tag>TXT_KEY_FUNCTIONALITY_EXTRAVOTESPERDIPLOMAT_TECH_INTERNET</Tag>
      <Text>ExtraVotesPerDiplomat1</Text>
    </Row>
    <Row>
      <Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_ADVANCED_ENGINE_DESC</Tag>
      <Text>先進引擎</Text>
    </Row>
    <Row>
      <Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_ADVANCED_ENGINE_CIV</Tag>
      <Text>Added using Indie Stone Tech Tree Editor.</Text>
    </Row>
    <Row>
      <Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_ADVANCED_ENGINE_HELP</Tag>
      <Text>Added using Indie Stone Tech Tree Editor.</Text>
    </Row>
    <Row>
      <Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_ADVANCED_ENGINE_QUOTE</Tag>
      <Text>'Some Famous Quote' - Some Famous Person</Text>
    </Row>
    <Row>
      <Tag>TXT_KEY_FUNCTIONALITY_INFLUENCESPREADMODIFIER_TECH_GLOBALIZATION</Tag>
      <Text>TourismBy100</Text>
    </Row>
    <Row>
      <Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_ARTIFICIAL_INTELLIGENCE_DESC</Tag>
      <Text>人工智能</Text>
    </Row>
    <Row>
      <Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_ARTIFICIAL_INTELLIGENCE_CIV</Tag>
      <Text>Added using Indie Stone Tech Tree Editor.</Text>
    </Row>
    <Row>
      <Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_ARTIFICIAL_INTELLIGENCE_HELP</Tag>
      <Text>Added using Indie Stone Tech Tree Editor.</Text>
    </Row>
    <Row>
      <Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_ARTIFICIAL_INTELLIGENCE_QUOTE</Tag>
      <Text>'Some Famous Quote' - Some Famous Person</Text>
    </Row>
    <Row>
      <Tag>TXT_KEY_FUNCTIONALITY_ALLOWSEMBARKING_TECH_ELECTRONICS</Tag>
      <Text>Embark</Text>
    </Row>
    <Row>
      <Tag>TXT_KEY_FUNCTIONALITY_EMBARKEDALLWATERPASSAGE_TECH_ELECTRONICS</Tag>
      <Text>OceanCross</Text>
    </Row>
    <Row>
      <Tag>TXT_KEY_FUNCTIONALITY_MAPVISIBLE_TECH_ELECTRONICS</Tag>
      <Text>RevealMap</Text>
    </Row>
    <Row>
      <Tag>TXT_KEY_FUNCTIONALITY_ALLOWEMBASSYTRADINGALLOWED_TECH_ELECTRONICS</Tag>
      <Text>Embassy</Text>
    </Row>
    <Row>
      <Tag>TXT_KEY_FUNCTIONALITY_OPENBORDERSTRADINGALLOWED_TECH_ELECTRONICS</Tag>
      <Text>OpenBorders</Text>
    </Row>
    <Row>
      <Tag>TXT_KEY_FUNCTIONALITY_DEFENSIVEPACTTRADINGALLOWED_TECH_ELECTRONICS</Tag>
      <Text>DefPact</Text>
    </Row>
    <Row>
      <Tag>TXT_KEY_FUNCTIONALITY_RESEARCHAGREEMENTTRADINGALLOWED_TECH_ELECTRONICS</Tag>
      <Text>ResearchAgreements</Text>
    </Row>
    <Row>
      <Tag>TXT_KEY_FUNCTIONALITY_BRIDGEBUILDING_TECH_ELECTRONICS</Tag>
      <Text>BridgesOnRivers</Text>
    </Row>
    <Row>
      <Tag>TXT_KEY_FUNCTIONALITY_ALLOWSWORLDCONGRESS_TECH_ELECTRONICS</Tag>
      <Text>WorldCongress</Text>
    </Row>
    <Row>
      <Tag>TXT_KEY_GENERIC_FUNCTIONALITY</Tag>
      <Text>Custom Generic</Text>
    </Row>
    <Row>
      <Tag>TXT_KEY_GENERIC_FUNCTIONALITY_EFFECT</Tag>
      <Text>Does something. Added by the Visual Tech Tree Editor.</Text>
    </Row>
    <Row>
      <Tag>TXT_KEY_FUNCTIONALITY_INTERNATIONALTRADEROUTESCHANGE_TECH_INTERNET</Tag>
      <Text>TradeRoute1</Text>
    </Row>
    <Update>
      <Set Text="建築學" />
      <Where Tag="TXT_KEY_TECH_ARCHITECTURE_DESC" />
    </Update>
    <Update>
      <Set Text="電子學的研究範疇便是電子在受控狀態下，在各種包括真空等各種介質中的行為模式。這門科學與電學科技並不相同，電學主要和電流的產生和輸送有關。電子學直到1950年代才從無線電學中獨立出來，成為一門學科。[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]電子電路主要被分為兩大類：類比電路和數位電路。類比電路通常由基礎電路排列組合而成，使用連續電壓，不過現今已經少用全為類比的電路了。數位電路為現代電腦和可程式邏輯控制器打下基礎，也是「邏輯代數」（即0與1）最常見的實質體現。[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]電子學的研究和發展和數學的發展緊密相關，擅長後者是學習前者的先決條件。無論是創造還是分析複雜的電路，都需要能夠解出帶有多項未知變數（比如某個特定位點的電壓和電流）的線性系統。因此，設計自動軟體套件可以大幅提升電路設計效率，這可是一件做起來相當微妙的工作。" />
      <Where Tag="TXT_KEY_TECH_ELECTRONICS_HELP" />
    </Update>
    <Update>
      <Set Text="天文學" />
      <Where Tag="TXT_KEY_TECH_ASTRONOMY_DESC" />
    </Update>
    <Update>
      <Set Text="行政事務" />
      <Where Tag="TXT_KEY_TECH_CIVIL_SERVICE_DESC" />
    </Update>
    <Update>
      <Set Text="貨幣" />
      <Where Tag="TXT_KEY_TECH_CURRENCY_DESC" />
    </Update>
    <Update>
      <Set Text="電子學" />
      <Where Tag="TXT_KEY_TECH_ELECTRONICS_DESC" />
    </Update>
    <Update>
      <Set Text="[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB]「消費類電子產品有一個基本法則--它的功能越來越強，它的價格越來越低。」[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB]--崔普·霍金斯[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB][TAB]" />
      <Where Tag="TXT_KEY_TECH_ELECTRONICS_QUOTE" />
    </Update>
    <Update>
      <Set Text="火藥" />
      <Where Tag="TXT_KEY_TECH_GUNPOWDER_DESC" />
    </Update>
    <Update>
      <Set Text="印刷術" />
      <Where Tag="TXT_KEY_TECH_PRINTING_PRESS_DESC" />
    </Update>
    <Update>
      <Set Text="可替換部件" />
      <Where Tag="TXT_KEY_TECH_REPLACEABLE_PARTS_DESC" />
    </Update>
    <Update>
      <Set Text="航海" />
      <Where Tag="TXT_KEY_TECH_SAILING_DESC" />
    </Update>
    <Update>
      <Set Text="神學" />
      <Where Tag="TXT_KEY_TECH_THEOLOGY_DESC" />
    </Update>
	<Update>
	  <Set Text="允許您建造提供[ICON_FOOD]食物的[COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT]穀倉[ENDCOLOR]以幫助您的城市繁榮發展。" />
	  <Where Tag="TXT_KEY_TECH_POTTERY_HELP" />
	</Update>
	<Update>
	  <Set Text="允許您的工人[COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT]砍伐叢林[ENDCOLOR]，清理地圖單元格以建造其它改良設施。還能讓您生產可以抵抗敵方騎乘單位的[COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT]長矛兵[ENDCOLOR]。" />
	  <Where Tag="TXT_KEY_TECH_BRONZE_WORKING_HELP" />
	</Update>
	<Update>
	  <Set Text="探明[ICON_RES_IRON][COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT]鐵礦[ENDCOLOR]，並允許您生產[COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT]劍士[ENDCOLOR]，一種需要鐵礦且極其強力的近戰單位。" />
	  <Where Tag="TXT_KEY_TECH_IRON_WORKING_HELP" />
	</Update>	  
  </Language_zh_Hant_HK>
</GameData>